[Music]
hi this is Thomas Lennon this is an at
midnight masterclass and I love wine I'm
a wine enthusiast uh and today I'm going
to show you just a little bit about uh
when you're tasting wine so you can
impress your friends at fancy
restaurants but also I thought it'd be
fun uh since I'm already blindfolded to
show you how to escape uh if your hands
have been zip
tied a lot of people smell corks when
they take wine people want to act like
they fancy so they go like that that is
absolutely nothing you're never going to
really learn much from smelling corks
what you want to do with a cork is look
at it because you want to see if it's
wet if the cork is dry the wine will be
positively ruined a lot of people in the
world uh are snobs about screw top wines
but I'll tell you a thing about a screw
top wine you will never get a corked
bottle of wine with a screw top I swear
to God I really felt like there was a
raccoon sneaking up on me as this was
happening but it was just a sound of the
cork rolled off the table right okay uh
so a lot of people look at Wines through
uh you can hold it up to the light and
you're looking at What's called the legs
that means just how much stays on the
side of the glass when you hold it up uh
and it could you know indicate if
there's like tannin in the wine or if
there's a lot of sugars if it's kind of
like a thick wine or not doesn't
necessarily mean if it's good or bad it
just is what the legs look like uh and
then there's the nose where you kind of
smell the one I stick my nose way in
[Music]
it and I smell it really hard because I
did a ton of cocaine in the '90s
so I don't have the most amazing sense
of smell uh a lot of people spin in
around reason you're spinning it one
it's fun to do if you've got attention
deficit and it's uh like a little fidget
spinner two it just as adding you're
getting more oxygen in the wine and the
air is you know opening it up and
letting it breathe so and then the
Finish is what it tastes like on your
tongue so you kind of get air what I
always do and it looks sort of tacky but
I I literally just suck air over the
wine on my tongue
but if you're in a really fancy
restaurant people will assume that you
know what you're doing and they won't
think it's
gross again I did a ton of cocaine in
the '90s so it's taking me a second oh
the other great thing about wine is it
gets as you get do this and you kind of
can be a smarty pants with your friends
it also gets you up there's a
ton of rules about wine guys
and I'm mostly a comedian um anyway
that's everything I know about tasting
wine uh get up guys then get kidnapped
and when you get kidnapped somebody
might zip tie your hands together and
when you do what you want to do is uh
from way up high use uh the force of
your body I'm going to slam my hands
down across my
midsection and uh basically use my
abdomen like a guillotine to to split me
out of these and they can be as tight as
they want they can be way bigger than
this too and 3 2 1
that's how to get out of zip ties that's
some of the stuff I know about wine and
this is an at midnight master
class I feel like the at midnight crew
just found an old napkin that's tied
around my face right now which is
hilarious but I'm also a major
germaphobe so we'll see how that goes
but I do feel like this was just a
napkin that somebody found right
uh